[
  {
    "question": "How can I test for blood glucose level?",
    "answer": "One way to test for blood glucose level is by using a glucometer. A glucometer is small and can be used at home, in clinics and health centres to aid in diabetes detection. The blood glucose test is a similar finger-prick test to indicate blood glucose level at that point in time. It is convenient and can be accurate if done properly. Anyone, even a child, can be taught to perform the test and it is essential for a person with diabetes to operate the glucometer. Another way is to take the HbA1c (haemoglobin A1c) test, which reflects average blood glucose control for a three-month period. Haemoglobin A1c in the red blood cells (glycohemoglobin) are glycated or sugar coated. The body usually replaces red blood cells every three months. This is usually done quarterly in the laboratory. The blood glucose and HbA1c tests are not universally accepted as diagnostic tests for diabetes mellitus. But, if the person has symptoms of diabetes mellitus with abnormal HbA1c and/or high blood glucose level on subsequent days, the doctor can then confirm the diagnosis.\nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Oral Glucose Tolerance Test (OGTT)?",
    "answer": "It is usually carried out to confirm if a person is suffering from diabetes. This test can also differentiate patients who have impaired fasting or glucose tolerance. Before taking the test, one must fast for at least eight hours before blood/plasma and urine samples are taken.\nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are ketones?",
    "answer": "Ketones are the by-products of fat metabolism. Ketones are acidic, and if excessive amounts accumulate in the body, can poison brain cells. This occurs when there is not enough insulin to allow glucose to enter the cells and fuel them, or when there are too much stress hormones. Excessive ketones in the blood can render a person unconscious. It can happen when a person suffers from type 1 diabetes mellitus and the onset is usually sudden. This is a serious condition called Diabetic Keto-Acidosis (DKA).\nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Impaired Glucose Tolerance (IGT)?",
    "answer": "Impaired glucose tolerance is a condition that occurs before one develops diabetes. It means that blood sugar levels are elevated but not elevated enough to warrant a diagnosis of diabetes. Usually, insulin and glucose levels are in equilibrium. If the blood glucose level is high, the body will produce more insulin to bring the glucose level down. This is called a feedback mechanism. \nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine, Healthline https://www.healthline.com/health/impaired-glucose-tolerance."
  },
  {
    "question": "I drink a lot of fruit juices or fizzy drinks. Does this cause diabetes?",
    "answer": "Your choice of beverage may not cause diabetes, as genetics also play a role in predisposing a person to diabetes. Nonetheless, fruit juices and fizzy drinks have high sugar content and are high in calories. When consumed in excess, these may cause obesity, which is a contributing factor for type 2 diabetes. Fruit juices are also high in fructose, another simple sugar like glucose. Over time, the pancreas will burn out and may not be able to produce sufficient insulin for the body to convert blood glucose into energy and to store glycogen. There will be a build-up of blood glucose in the red blood cells. This is the main sign of untreated or uncontrolled diabetes.\nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "I don't quite understand the concepts of insulin and glucose in our body.",
    "answer": "Put simply, the pancreas is the factory that produces insulin. Insulin is the key to control blood glucose. Glucose is fuel for the body. \nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "What happens when I eat?",
    "answer": "More than 75% of our food, mainly carbohydrates, are broken down into glucose when digested. Glucose enters the bloodstream, and the level of blood glucose begins to rise. When our body senses an increase in blood glucose, it sends a signal to the pancreas to produce more insulin to lower the blood glucose level. If the blood glucose level is still high, more insulin will be produced to enter the bloodstream. The insulin acts as a key to unlock the body's cells and allow glucose to pass from the bloodstream into the cells. The blood glucose level falls as glucose is transferred to the cells. The body cells use the glucose for fuel.\nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can we store glucose in our body?",
    "answer": "Yes, glucose is stored as glycogen mainly in the liver, muscles, and fat tissues. Our body knows that glucose is a good product, and the kidneys act as filters to reabsorb the glucose into our blood by coating the red blood cells and transferring them to the muscle and liver to be stored as glycogen. When the liver, the main store, is full, excess glucose will be stored as triglycerides in the fat tissues. When our body needs energy, the stored glucose and glycogen in the liver will be broken down by insulin and converted to energy.\nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "How does Type 1 differ from Type 2 diabetes?",
    "answer": "Type 1 diabetes is an auto-immune disease, where the pancreas is not producing insulin at all. Type 2 diabetes is a lifestyle disease, where the pancreas is not working efficiently or sufficiently. The onset of type 1 diabetes is often sudden, affecting children and young people below the age of 30. While more young and overweight people have developed type 2 diabetes in recent years, it usually occurs in the 40s. The cause of type 1 diabetes may be unknown; however, some people develop it after a bout of illness such as a viral infection. For type 2 diabetes, many have a family history of the disease. People with type 1 diabetes will need insulin injections for life, but type 2 diabetes can be controlled by adopting proper diet, exercise, and with medication.\nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is Type 2 Diabetes Mellitus?",
    "answer": "Type 2 diabetes develops because the body becomes insulin resistant or does not respond effectively to natural insulin. This is possibly due to a defective gene factor. Initially, the pancreas may produce more insulin to cope with the increased blood glucose and to break down the food we eat. Usually, the patient needs anti-diabetic tablets or Oral Hypoglycaemic Agent (OHA) to control blood glucose. Eventually, the pancreas suffers a burnout and produces low levels of insulin. The diabetic patient may then need insulin injections.\nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why is diabetes more common nowadays?",
    "answer": "In the past, we did not have many fast-food restaurants, high calorie beverages and rich foods. Fast food contains saturated fat, which is not easily broken down by the body and tends to deposit inside the blood vessels. Blood glucose and cholesterol levels will rise within the blood vessels. We also led more active lifestyles and children played outdoors instead of sitting in front of the television or computer. Seldom did we see children who were obese or very overweight. Today, we lead sedentary lives; some say that diabetes is a “New World Syndrome” – a disease due to urbanisation, high calorie diets, poor sedentary lifestyles, and bad habits. \nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "I often skip meals or eat only when I am very hungry. Why do I still have high blood glucose levels?",
    "answer": "Many people today tend to skip meals or eat at irregular hours because of work or poor lifestyle. When you skip a meal or eat only when you are very hungry, it is likely that you will have a heavy meal later. Your pancreas has to work doubly hard to produce more insulin to digest the food. When you skip a meal, the liver may release glucose into the blood. Over a period of time, the liver ‘learns to release glucose at odd times'. At the same time, the pancreas does not work efficiently, cannot produce sufficient or effective insulin. This is why some people with diabetes have high blood glucose levels, even when they do not eat. \nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why do people with diabetes have heart diseases?",
    "answer": "Diabetes and heart diseases have a synergistic effect, which means that if a person has diabetes, he is likely to have heart disease as well and vice versa. That is why people with diabetes usually have more than one health problem. When the blood is thick with cholesterol and glucose, it increases the resistance and blood pressure. Just imagine, when a person has high blood pressure, the heart will have to pump harder to circulate blood in the body. Over a period of time, the blood vessels can become damaged from stress, illness, poor lifestyle, and diet. \nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why do I feel thirsty all the time and experience frequent urination?",
    "answer": "When blood glucose level is too high and insulin is absent, the kidneys cannot reabsorb the excess glucose. This excess is then excreted in the urine. Whatever you drink is hence siphoned out of the body in the urine. The cells experience a water shortage, you feel thirsty, and your brain will signal you to drink more water. Frequent urination can be an early sign of high blood glucose levels. If you have been experiencing frequent urination, it is advisable for you to have your blood glucose level checked.\nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why are diabetics prone to skin infections?",
    "answer": "When blood glucose is deposited inside the small blood vessels near the skin surface, the sluggish blood flow makes it easier for germs and fungi to multiply on the skin, especially in our warm and humid climate. Diabetics are prone to infections of the skin, mouth, urinary tract, and genital areas.\nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "I always feel hungry and eat a lot. But I noticed that I still lose weight. Why does this happen?",
    "answer": "If diabetes is not well-controlled, this can cause your body to starve, as well as you to feel hungry and eat more than ever. We need insulin because it acts as the key, to allow glucose to go in and out of the cells in the muscles and liver. When you do not have insulin, the muscles and liver cannot release the stored glucose or glycogen and convert it into fuel for your body. The body will then have to use fat and convert it into energy for the heart, lungs, and other body systems to function. This is why a person with undiagnosed or poorly controlled diabetes may lose weight.\nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the common gastro-intestinal problems associated with diabetes?",
    "answer": "When a person has very high blood glucose levels, constipation is common. Initially, one may suffer from indigestion, nausea, and vomiting. Later, one may suffer from diarrhoea as the body tries to get rid of the waste.\nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "How does diabetes affect my vision?",
    "answer": "Blood glucose that are deposited in the small blood vessels can cause them to narrow and increase blood pressure in the eyes, causing glaucoma. When glaucoma occurs, the narrow-damaged blood vessels may leak, and this is called retinopathy. Cataract is a white layer over the lens of the eye. If diabetes is coupled with hypertension, it may result in a tear of the retina and cause severe bleeding of the eyes, which can lead to blindness. Hence, it is important to seek prompt medical treatment if you see ‘floaters', ‘curtain falling' or something unusual happening to your vision.\nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "Why do I sometimes feel numb in my limbs, toes, and fingers?",
    "answer": "This is usually due to poor blood circulation. High levels of cholesterol and glucose in the blood can cause nerve damage or impede blood flow. Usually, numbness in the extremities, or the arms and legs, is an early sign of diabetes. With poorly controlled diabetes, you may first feel a tingling or burning sensation, or even numbness, when your blood glucose level is very high. Subsequently, the pain may worsen and is often described as a ‘stingy bite' or ‘nerve pain'. If the blood glucose level is not controlled over a period of time, you may lose all sensation in your lower limbs and feet. If you are experiencing numbness, it is best to consult a doctor to determine the cause. \nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "How does diabetes incapacitate?",
    "answer": "Some diabetics may accidentally cut the toe or foot and end up with a limb amputation. With poor blood circulation, the person may have lost all sensation in his feet and cannot feel pain. There is poor healing when infection sets in. The tissue in the leg becomes gangrenous and amputation may be required to save the patient's life. If you have diabetes, it is not safe to walk about barefooted. Pebble-stone reflexology is also highly discouraged because the sharp, rough stones may cut the feet.\nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can diabetes ruin my sex life?",
    "answer": "Our reproductive system is rich in blood supply and has many nerves. Our nerves are located just next to the blood vessels and can be affected if diabetes is poorly controlled. If you are a man with diabetes, you may experience impotence or erectile dysfunction, and face difficulty when engaging in sexual intercourse. It is thus encouraged to seek help in the early stages of diabetes, where impotence can be prevented or resolved through proper control of the blood glucose level. If blood glucose is not controlled over a period of time, neuropathy or permanent nerve damage may set in.\nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "What do kidneys do?",
    "answer": "Kidneys are the main excretory organs with millions of microscopic filtering units called nephrons. Kidneys filter the blood, removing urea and waste products, excess sugar, salts, and water in the urine. Kidneys control the amount of water in your body. The more you drink, the more urine excreted out.\nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can certain fruit or vegetable juices lower my blood glucose level?",
    "answer": "Many people believe bitter gourd juice counteracts the sweetness of blood glucose. This has not been scientifically proven. Others believe that celery and green apple juices have the same effect. These beliefs are also scientifically unproven. Fibre, however, can lower blood glucose and cholesterol levels. It is recommended that people with diabetes take 20 to 35g of fibre per day.\nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine, Ministry of Health Diabetes Mellitus Booklet."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can Chinese herbs or medicine lower my blood glucose level?",
    "answer": "It is vital that you let your doctor know if you are taking any Chinese herbs or vitamin supplements. Some Chinese medicines can interact adversely with your prescribed diabetes medication.\nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is so good about a high fibre diet?",
    "answer": "A high fibre diet consists of 2 servings of leafy vegetables and 2 servings of fruit per day. Fibre makes us feel full and we are unlikely to overeat. It stabilises the blood glucose level because it causes glucose to be absorbed into our bodies at a slower rate and gives insulin more time to work effectively. Fibre also prevents constipation and is good for the digestive system. \nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can diabetics consume more brown rice and cereal?",
    "answer": "Brown rice and cereal are carbohydrates and a person with diabetes should limit their carbohydrate intake, as recommended by their dieticians. Brown rice, however, is considered to be healthier than white rice because it is unpolished and has more vitamins and fibre. The fibre in brown rice will keep a person feeling full longer.\nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "Does preserved food have higher calories?",
    "answer": "Yes, most preserved foods have higher calories because sugar is often added when the food is processed. Many vitamins are also lost when food is processed. It is always healthier to eat fresh produce. When buying processed food, you need to read food labels for details and not to be misled by words such as ‘sugar-free' and ‘cholesterol-free'.\nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the difference between “No sugar” and “Sugar-free”?",
    "answer": "When the label on a bottle states, “No Sugar Added”, it means that the manufacturer does not add sugar to the product. However, the sugar content in jam comes from the fruit (fructose), and moderate consumption is advised. There is natural sugar in most of the foods we eat. For example, milk sugar (lactose) is found in dairy foods such as cheese and yoghurt. Chocolate sugar (maltose) can be found in malted beverages, and all types of flour, when absorbed in the digestive system, become glucose.\nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "How can I get better at reading food labels?",
    "answer": "Here are some tips to help you read food labels.\n    • Serving sizes and servings per container are located right at the top of the nutritional information panel. \n    • “Total carbohydrate” refers to the amount of starch, sugar, and fibres present in the food. It is important to bear in mind that sugar has already been included as total carbohydrate.\n    • To compare between different brands of the same food, use the “per100g” column on the nutritional panel.\nSource: Red Ants Crawling to My Urine."
  },
  {
    "question": "Can I still consume sweeteners if I am diabetic?",
    "answer": "Sweeteners can be safely consumed by diabetics as they do not increase blood sugar levels. They should, however, be taken in small amounts and occasionally. Excessive intake is not advisable because some sweeteners, based on certain forms of carbohydrate source, still contain calories. Sugar substitutes that are commonly available in Singapore include:\n    • Aspartame (found in Equal)\n    • Saccharin (Hermestas)\n    • Sucralose (Splenda)\n    • Stevia, a herbal product (Equal Stevia, Jovia)\n    • Xylitol, a plant-based sugar alcohol (XyloSweet)\n    • Acesulfame Potassium (found in carbonated drinks and protein shakes)\nSource: HealthXChange, HealthHub\nhttps://www.healthxchange.sg/food-nutrition/food-tips/artificial-sweeteners-how-safe\nhttps://www.healthhub.sg/programmes/191/nutrition-hub/eat-less#:~:text=For%20baking%20and%20cooking%2C%20avoid,acesulfame%20K%20and%20sucralose%20instead\n\nQ&A taken from HealthH."
  },
  {
    "question": "What does insulin resistance mean?",
    "answer": "Insulin resistance means some body cells don't react properly to insulin – they cannot be unlocked to let in glucose from the bloodstream. \nSource: HealthHub\nhttps://www.healthhub.sg/a-z/diseases-and-conditions/676/pocket-guide-to-diabetes."
  },
  {
    "question": "What causes insulin resistance and what can I do about it?",
    "answer": "One possible cause of insulin resistance is obesity and a high-calorie diet. A diet high in carbs, sugar, and fat increases calorie intake and contributes to obesity. Losing 5 to 10% of our body weight is enough to increase insulin sensitivity. Use My Healthy Plate or consult a dietician to guide you on how much to eat. Another cause of insulin resistance is lack of exercise. Do light workouts like walking and swimming to improve insulin insensitivity and help you lose excess weight. Insulin resistance may also be caused by factors like ethnicity, certain diseases, steroid use, some medications, older age, sleep problems, and smoking.\nSource: HealthHub\nhttps://www.healthhub.sg/a-z/diseases-and-conditions/676/pocket-guide-to-diabetes\n."
  },
  {
    "question": "What does insulin shortage mean?",
    "answer": "When there's a shortage of insulin, glucose cannot be transported into body cells effectively, leaving excess glucose in the bloodstream.\nSource: HealthHub\nhttps://www.healthhub.sg/a-z/diseases-and-conditions/676/pocket-guide-to-diabetes."
  },
  {
    "question": "What causes insulin shortage and what can I do about it?",
    "answer": "Insulin shortage can be caused your diet and an overworked pancreas. Carbs and sugar get broken down into glucose. A high-carb, high-sugar diet means we need more insulin to process all that glucose. Over time, this could overwork and damage the pancreas, causing it to produce less insulin. To combat this, avoid eating too many portions of refined carbs (e.g., white rice, white bread) and sugary foods. Another possible factor that causes insulin shortage is obesity and a fatty pancreas. Obesity causes fat to gather in the pancreas. The more fat in the pancreas, the less insulin it makes. To shed pancreatic fat, you need to lose excess weight.\nSource: HealthHub\nhttps://www.healthhub.sg/a-z/diseases-and-conditions/676/pocket-guide-to-diabetes."
  },
  {
    "question": "Who is most at risk of developing type 2 diabetes?",
    "answer": "You're more likely to develop type 2 diabetes if you:\n- Are overweight or obese (BMI of 23.0 kg/m² or higher)\n- Lead an inactive lifestyle\n- Are 40 years old and above\n- Have a parent or sibling with diabetes\n- Have a history of gestational diabetes\n- Have impaired glucose tolerance or impaired fasting glucose\n- Have abnormal blood cholesterol or lipid levels\n- Have high blood pressure\nSource: HealthHub\nhttps://www.healthhub.sg/a-z/diseases-and-conditions/676/pocket-guide-to-diabetes."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are some common symptoms of diabetes?",
    "answer": "Diabetes symptoms might be so mild they go unnoticed. Get yourself screened if you notice some of these symptoms, even if you feel well. Early detection and treatment can reduce risk of complications.\n- Blurred vision\n- Feeling hungry all the time\n- Feeling thirsty all the time (despite drinking lots of water)\n- Frequent urination\n- Losing weight\n- Poor healing of wounds and/or infection\n- Feeling tired and weak\n- Numbness or tingling in hands, arms, feet, and legs\n- Feeling of nausea and/or vomiting\nSource: HealthHub\nhttps://www.healthhub.sg/a-z/diseases-and-conditions/676/pocket-guide-to-diabetes."
  },
  {
    "question": "What kinds of complications can diabetes cause?",
    "answer": "Diabetes can cause microvascular (small vessel) diseases like nerve damage, retinopathy, and kidney failure. To detect these early, go for regular screening. Diabetes can also cause macrovascular (medium and large vessel) complications like stroke, heart attack, and reduced blood circulation. Some ways to prevent these complications are exercising, losing excess weight, and quitting smoking.\nSource: HealthHub\nhttps://www.healthhub.sg/a-z/diseases-and-conditions/676/pocket-guide-to-diabetes."
  },
  {
    "question": "How does diabetes lead to nerve damage?",
    "answer": "Diabetes can lead to nerve damage and loss of feeling in the feet. This means your feet can be injured without you feeling it, which increases the risk for ulcers and infections. To combat this, go for regular foot screening.\nSource: HealthHub\nhttps://www.healthhub.sg/a-z/diseases-and-conditions/676/pocket-guide-to-diabetes."
  },
  {
    "question": "How does diabetes lead to retinopathy?",
    "answer": "Diabetes may lead to retinopathy, which is damage to blood vessels in the eye, and in turn, lead to blindness. To prevent this, go for regular retinal photography screening.\nSource: HealthHub\nhttps://www.healthhub.sg/a-z/diseases-and-conditions/676/pocket-guide-to-diabetes."
  },
  {
    "question": "How does diabetes lead to kidney failure?",
    "answer": "Diabetes increases the risk for kidney disease. This can lead to kidney failure, which requires dialysis to treat. Go for regular urine tests to check for microalbumin/protein and regular blood tests to evaluate kidney function.\nSource: HealthHub\nhttps://www.healthhub.sg/a-z/diseases-and-conditions/676/pocket-guide-to-diabetes."
  },
  {
    "question": "How does diabetes lead to stroke?",
    "answer": "Diabetes may damage blood vessels in the brain, which can lead to stroke. If any signs of stroke appear, go to the hospital immediately.\nSource: HealthHub\nhttps://www.healthhub.sg/a-z/diseases-and-conditions/676/pocket-guide-to-diabetes."
  },
  {
    "question": "How does diabetes lead to heart attack?",
    "answer": "Diabetes may cause damage and blockages to the blood vessels of the heart, which can lead to a heart attack. If you experience chest pains, consult a doctor immediately.\nSource: HealthHub\nhttps://www.healthhub.sg/a-z/diseases-and-conditions/676/pocket-guide-to-diabetes."
  },
  {
    "question": "How does diabetes lead to reduced blood circulation?",
    "answer": "Diabetes can reduce or block blood flow to your legs, which may lead to gangrene (tissue death due to loss of blood supply) and even amputation. If you experience pain in the leg brought on by walking that is relieved with rest, or skin turning a darker colour (e.g., brown, purplish-blue, black), see a doctor immediately.\nSource: HealthHub\nhttps://www.healthhub.sg/a-z/diseases-and-conditions/676/pocket-guide-to-diabetes."
  },
  {
    "question": "How do I look out for hypoglycaemia?",
    "answer": "These are the common signs and symptoms of hypoglycaemia:\n- Hunger\n- Changes in behaviour (e.g., moodiness, confusion)\n- Unconsciousness\n- Tiredness\n- Trembling hands/nervousness\n- Sweating\n- Dizziness/headache\nSource: HealthHub\nhttps://www.healthhub.sg/a-z/diseases-and-conditions/676/pocket-guide-to-diabetes."
  },
  {
    "question": "What should I do if I think I have hypoglycaemia?",
    "answer": "Check your blood glucose levels. If it is low, drink half a glass of sweetened beverages (e.g., juice). Alternatively, eat sweets or glucose tablets.\nSource: HealthHub\nhttps://www.healthhub.sg/a-z/diseases-and-conditions/676/pocket-guide-to-diabetes."
  },
  {
    "question": "How do I look out for hyperglycaemia?",
    "answer": "These are the common signs and symptoms of hyperglycaemia:\n- Feeling tired and weak\n- Frequent urination\n- Feeling of nausea and/or vomiting\n- Blurred vision\n- Feeling thirsty all the time\nSource: HealthHub\nhttps://www.healthhub.sg/a-z/diseases-and-conditions/676/pocket-guide-to-diabetes."
  },
  {
    "question": "I am sick. What should I do?",
    "answer": "Here are some tips to manage sick days:\n- See a doctor\n- Get plenty of sleep\n- Eat regular meals\n- Drink plenty of plain water\n- Take medication/insulin as per normal\n- Check blood glucose levels more frequently (if unusually high, see a doctor immediately)\nSource: HealthHub\nhttps://www.healthhub.sg/a-z/diseases-and-conditions/676/pocket-guide-to-diabetes."
  },
  {
    "question": "What kind of carbs should I consume?",
    "answer": "We need carbohydrates in our diet for energy, but some carbs are better than others when it comes to managing diabetes. Choose those that raise your blood glucose slowly. Try to choose wholegrains more often and refined grains less often. Examples of wholegrains are brown rice, oats, wholemeal bread, and whole wheat flour. Refined grains refer to white bread, white rice, and fine wheat flour. Basmati and cous cous fall in between these two categories.\nSource: HealthHub\nhttps://www.healthhub.sg/a-z/diseases-and-conditions/676/pocket-guide-to-diabetes."
  },
  {
    "question": "What are the benefits of high-fibre food?",
    "answer": "Firstly, fibre from fruits, veggies, and grains fills you up. You stay full longer and are less likely to overeat. Secondly, fibre takes longer to digest. Slower digestion means a slower rise in blood glucose, compared to food with little/no fibre. This helps you better manage your blood glucose.\nSource: HealthHub\nhttps://www.healthhub.sg/a-z/diseases-and-conditions/676/pocket-guide-to-diabetes."
  },
  {
    "question": "What foods are highest in fibre? ",
    "answer": "Here are some common sources of fibre:\n- Vegetables\n- Fruit\n- Wholegrain products\n- Beans, legumes, and nuts\nSource: HealthHub\nhttps://www.healthhub.sg/a-z/diseases-and-conditions/676/pocket-guide-to-diabet."
  }
]
